Rachel Lewis

(918) 346-1751 <u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

Self-motivated, quick-learning software engineer specializing in full stack web development. Detailoriented and organized with demonstrated skill in balancing multiple priorities under tight deadlines. Flexible, proactive, and thorough, with a continual focus on data organization and code reusability.

EXPERIENCE

LEAVE OF ABSENCE (2015 - 2020)

Attended to family-related medical issue.

COMPLIANCE SPECIALIST

CIMAREX ENERGY Co. (2013 – 2015)

Provided ad hoc support to 6 project leads on 8 long-term projects. Maintained and updated 2 databases to support information needs. Wrote and maintained documentation as project lead for 3 biennial projects.

- Organized data structures to optimize data collection and analyzed trends to restructure submission development, saving \$50K in 6 months.
- Coordinated with team to develop new automated strategy for submitting legal documentation. Completed 200+ submissions in 1 month for one-time project and doubled overall weekly average.
- Researched and corrected 10,000+ data points during 5-month period utilizing 9 distinct sources, increasing confidence in data by 80%.

BUSINESS ANALYST

LEWIS OIL & GAS (2013 – 2015)

Developed budget and expenditure plans, proposed recommendations, and secured contracts. Primary focus on implementing strategies to leverage statistical company strengths.

- Established financial system to analyze account patterns resulting in immediate savings of up to 30% per month.
- Produced research reports for up to 10 sites/week including recommendations, doubling number of strong producers in 3 years.

EDUCATION

University of Arkansas Bachelor of Arts, International Relations, Magna cum Laude

Holberton School (January 2021 – June 2022) Software Engineering, Full-Stack Web Development

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, C. Frontend: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind. Frameworks: Flask, Django, NodeJS, ExpressJS. Tools: jQuery, Unix/Linux, Git. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, AWS, MongoDB